Weddings are expensive affairs – there’s nothing new or surprising in that statement.
举办婚礼是件开销不菲的事——这话一点也不新鲜。
When we talk about the costs of a wedding, we often think about the financial toll on the person paying for it.
当我们谈论婚礼的花费时，往往会想到买单者要承受的经济压力。
The outlay on tiered cakes, the dress with a long train, appliques and veil, and canapes at the reception can all add up.
多层蛋糕、拖尾带贴花的婚纱和面纱、婚宴上的开胃小食，这些开销加起来数目不小。
But what about the guests?
但宾客们的开销呢？
The cost to your friends and family to attend.
那些前来赴宴的亲友们要付出的成本，却常常被忽略。
The first thing to think about when attending is the price of getting there.
出席婚礼，首先要考虑的就是往返路费。
Even just a few hundred miles from where you live can bring some expenses – be it transport or staying in a hotel.
哪怕只是离家几百英里的距离，也会产生交通费、住宿费之类的开销。
But some people like to tie the knot in exotic locations, thinking it will make their special day even more special – on a beach in front of palm trees rather than somewhere closer to home.
但有些人偏喜欢在充满异域风情的地方举办婚礼，他们觉得这样能让这个特殊的日子更难忘——比如在棕榈树环绕的海滩上，而非离家更近的地方。
Going to far-flung corners of the Earth to watch the event can really be a dealbreaker for some when deciding if they can make it.
对有些人来说，要远赴天涯海角参加婚礼，会成为他们决定是否出席的关键阻碍因素。
Then there is the gift.
接下来就是礼金和礼物的问题。
What do you give a person on their wedding day?
婚礼当天，该给新人送点什么呢？
In some cultures, asking for money isn’t the done thing.
在一些文化里，直接索要礼金是不合时宜的做法。
Sometimes the bride and groom may issue a list of items they want to receive that you have to pick from.
有时新人会列出一份想要的礼物清单，让宾客从中挑选。
But what do you buy?
可到底该买什么呢？
And if it’s money, how much do you give them?
如果是送礼金，又该送多少？
How much is too much?
多少算多哪？
These are questions all attendees face – give too little and you may cause offence, too much and you may be out of pocket.
这些都是每位宾客都会面临的难题——送太少怕失礼，送太多又会让自己手头拮据。
And of course, you don’t want to be outdone by a friend giving more than you.
而且，没人愿意在礼金数额上被朋友比下去。
Finally, the last thing you want to feel when going to a wedding is regret about the amount you’ve spent.
最后，参加一场婚礼，最不想感受到的就是为自己花出去的钱而后悔。
If you give a good gift and spend a lot on getting there, and the event isn’t great, or the food at the reception isn’t perfect, you might feel a little resentment.
如果你精心准备了贵重礼物，又花了不少钱奔波赴宴，结果婚礼办得不尽人意，或是婚宴的菜品难以下咽，心里难免会生出些许怨气。
Therefore, only give what you can afford to give.
因此，一切都要量力而行。
Weddings can be expensive for everyone concerned. But people often overlook the cost for guests.
婚礼对每个相关的人来说，都可能是一笔不小的开销，但人们常常忽略宾客的花费。
In the end, though, that special day is supposed to be a celebration of love above anything else.
不过说到底，这个特殊的日子，终究是一场以爱为核心的庆典。